Preliminary Guide to the Kiev Foundation graphics arts and artifacts collection, 1493-1969 K0005
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Kiev Foundation Graphics Arts and Artifacts Collection
1493-1969
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
K0005
7 Linear Feet
The collection includes prints, posters, cartoons, one Yellow Star of David Badge, postcards and other Judaica, much of it related to antisemitism.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
The graphic arts collection is an artificial collection of materials donated primarily by the Kiev Foundation after the original donation of the I. Edward Kiev Judaica Collection in 1996.
Historical Note
The graphic arts and artifacts collection in an artificial collection of materials donated primarily by the Kiev Family Trust after the original donation of the I. Edward Kiev Judaica Collection in 1996.
This is an open collection and materials continue to be acquired.
Collection Scope and Content
The collection includes prints, posters, one Yellow Star of David Badge, cartoons, postcards and other Judaica, much of it related to antisemitism.
Recent acquisitions include the purchase of 30 original postcards from artist E. M. Lilien.
Collection Organization
Organized into three series: Jewish art, antisemitica, and miscellaneous artifacts.
Antisemitism; Jews; Art, Jewish; Kiev Foundation; Lilien, Ephraim Mose
- Jewish art, 1910-1948; K0005 Series 1; 2 Linear Feet; 1 Linear feet (Box 14, Box 15, Box 1, Box 3)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series consists of graphic materials which were purchased after the donation of the original collection by the estate of I. Edward Kiev. There are roughly ninety items, which date from about 1910 to 1920. One box contains postcards depicting the work of Ephraim Mose Lilien, a Zionist iconographer and prominent contributor to the Art Nouveau movement. The other contains lithographs by the artist Hermann Struck, from the book, "Das Osjische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Both Lilien and Struck contributed works to an art exhibition held at the Fifth Zionist Congress in 1901, which helped establish Jewish visual art as a legitimate component of the Jewish cultural resurgence.
  - Lieder Des Volkes [Songs of the People], 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    Reverse of postcard states that the illustration was originally from the book Lieder Des Ghetto
  - Spaniolischer Jude, 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Reverse of postcard states that the illustration was originally from the book Erez Israel und sein Volk
  - Aus Galizien [From Galizien], 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Die Erschscaffung des Menschen [The Creation of Man], 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Reverse of postcard states that the illustration was originally from the book Lieder des Ghetto
  - Aus Der Buchara [From the Buchara], 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Affium-Karahissar, 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Die Trane auf dem Eisen, 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Sturm [The Storm], 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Rahab, Die Jerichonitin [Rahab, of Jericho], 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Reverse of postcard states that the illustration was originally from the book Juda
  - An Der Nahmaschine [At the Sewing Machine], 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Das Trauerlied [Song of Mourning], 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Widmung [Dedication], 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Absalom-Denkmal [Absalom monument], 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Morgenzeitung [Morning Paper], 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Lesender Junger Jude aus der Buchara [Jewish man reading, from Buchara], 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Schwarzer Jude Aus Afrika [A Black Jew from Africa], 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Harfenspielerin [The Harpist], 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Die Engel [The Angels], 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Enak Vor Gomorrha [Enak before Gomorrha], 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Sodoms Ruinen [Sodom's Ruins], 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Das Stille Lied [Silent Song], 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Lieder De Arbeit [Work Song], 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Lieder Des Lebens [Songs of Life], 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Mein Kind [My Child], 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Friedhof [Cemetery], 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Reverse of postcard states that the illustration was originally from the book
  - Ellul Melodien [Elul Melodies], 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Passah [Passover], 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Reverse of postcard states that the illustration was originally from the book Juda. Also referred to as Galut [Exile].
  - Die Wessagung des Jesaia [The Pointing saying of the Jesaia], 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Der Jüdische Mai [The Jewish May], 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Die Gesänge des Jehuda [The Singing of the Jehuda], 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Young girl with doll, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 41)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-01.
  - Young woman with scarf, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 42)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-02
  - Young woman with scarf and shawl, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 43)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-03.
  - Portrait of a young woman, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 44)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-04.
  - Portrait of a young woman, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 45)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-05.
  - Profile portrait of a young woman, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 46)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-06.
  - Profile portrait of a young woman, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 47)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-07.
  - Portrait of woman, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 48)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-08.
  - Portrait of woman, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 49)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-09.
  - Young woman writing, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 50)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-10.
  - Old woman with scarf, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 51)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-11.
  - Old woman in shawl, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 52)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-12.
  - Old woman sitting, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 53)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-13.
  - Young child, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 54)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-14.
  - Young boy in cap, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 55)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-15.
  - Young boy in cap, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 56)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-16.
  - Young boy with winter hat, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 57)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-17.
  - Young boy with hat, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 58)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-18.
  - Young beggar, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 59)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-19.
  - Young man with glasses, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 60)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-20.
  - Portrait of man, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 61)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-21.
  - Portrait of old man with cap, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 62)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-22.
  - Portrait of man with scarf, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 63)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-23.
  - Portrait of old man with cap, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 64)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-24.
  - Old man with pipe, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 65)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-25.
  - Old man with pipe, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 66)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-26.
  - Old man with cap, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 67)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-27.
  - Profile of old man with cap, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 68)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-28.
  - Man with cap, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 69)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-29.
  - Man with cap, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 70)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-30.
  - Man with cane, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 71)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-31.
  - Profile of man, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 72)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-32.
  - Old man, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 73)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-33.
  - Old man, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 74)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-34.
  - Man sitting, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 75)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-35.
  - Old man reading, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 76)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-36.
  - Man reading, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 77)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-37.
  - Man sitting in library, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 78)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-38.
  - Old man reading, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 79)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-39.
  - Man reading, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 80)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-40.
  - Young boy reading, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 81)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-41.
  - Young man with books under his arm, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 82)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-42.
  - Rabbi reading, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 83)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-43.
  - Man with lulov and etrog, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 84)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-44.
  - Man pulling cart, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 85)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-45.
  - Man with bucket, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 86)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-46.
  - Man carrying sack, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 87)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-47.
  - Tailor, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 88)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-48.
  - Shoemaker, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 89)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-49.
  - Watchmaker, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 90)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-50.
  - Synagogue, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 91)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-51.
  - Rabbi's house, 1920 ca. (Box 3, Folder 92)
    From the book, "Das Ostjüdische Antlitz" [The Face of Eastern European Jewry], published in 1920. Number given by donor: GW-05-52.
  - Old Jew of Jaffa, 1905 (Box 3, Folder 93)
    "Alter Jude aus Jaffa"; number given by donor: GW-05-53
  - Heinrich Heine, Undated (Box 3, Folder 94)
    Profile portrait etching of Heinrich Heine signed by Hermann Struck. Etching is numbered 77/100. Number given by donor: GW-05-54.
  - Letter from Hermann Struck to Dr. Schlesinger, March 4, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    Struck's response to Dr. Schlesinger's request that he prepare title illustrations for a publication.
  - Declaration of the establishment of the State of Israel, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 120)
    Includes a seperate English translation. Box contains an English biography of Szyk.
  - Six Jewish Festivals by Arthur Szyk, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 121)
    Box contains a English biography of Szyk.
  - The United States of America by Arthur Szyk, 1945 (Box 14, Folder 122)
  - History of Israel by Arthur Szyk, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 123)
  - Lincoln's Second Inaugural by Arthur Szyk, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 124)
  - Hillel by Arthur Szyk, undated (Box 14, Folder 125)
  - Head of an Old Man in a Cap, 1911 (Box 15, Folder 126)
  - Washington Crossing the Delaware; MacArthur in Australia by Arthur Szyk, After c. 1942; 1 folder(s) (Box 15, Folder 129)
    "Washington Crossing the Delaware", Arthur Szyk [published Paris, 1931] and "MacArthur in Australia", Arthur Szyk [published c. 1942-1945]; Double-sided matted sheet; 14 1/16" x 18 1/16" including 1/8" thick mat
  - Baruch Ata Bevuach, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 130)
    Facsimile print of 19th century wall poster for sukkah [2001]. Reproduced from Yitzhak Einhorn Collection, Tel Aviv, by The Western Wall Heritage Foundation. Letter and information sheet about print also included, (print) 14 1/2" x 11 1/4".
  - Ballad of the Doomed Jews of Europe, Arthur Szyk (Box 15, Folder 131)
    Published New York, 1943;(photocopy); 8 1/2" x 11"
  - Razzle-Dazzle, frontispiece illustrated by Arthur Szyk, c. 1942 (Box 15, Folder 134)
    Frontispiece published in Saroyan, William. Razzle-dazzle: or The human ballet, opera and circus: or There's something I got to tell you: being many kinds of short plays, as well as the story of writing them. New York: Harcourt, Brace and Company, (first edition) 1942. 10 1/2" x 8 1/2"
  - 12 Original Photos of the Museum Tel-Aviv (postcard set), Undated (Box 15, Folder 135)
    3.5" x 5.5". Yair Publishing Co. Ltd., Tel Aviv. Gift of Dr. Samuel Halperin.
  - Beautiful Women: Ukiyoe- Bijin Ga, 1982 (Map-folder 2)
    General Note
    Exhibition poster, The Tikotin Museum of Japanese Art, Haifa, 1982; 26 13/16" x 37 1/16"
  - Building Jerusalem, 1986 (Map-folder 3)
    Exhibition poster, The Israel Museum, Jerusalem, 1986; 26 1/2" x 38 3/4" x 3/16"
  - The Holy Land in Maps, Views and Photographs of the 15th-19th Centuries, 1986 (Map-folder 4)
    Exhibition poster, The Israel Museum, Jerusalem, 1986; 24 3/4" x 39 1/8" x 1/8"
  - Sheviti, After 1978 (Map-folder 5)
    Reproduction: Jerusalem, Haktav Institute, undated; original created by "Isaac", Elul 1978; 26 3/8" x 37" x 3/16"
  - Untitled print of watercolor with rainbow arching over a city, c. 1967 - 1990 (Map-folder 6)
    Raffi Kaiser (b. 1931), undated, marked 33/200, 34 1/8" x 26" including 1/8" thick mat
  - Ein Gedi- Dead Sea Landscape, Undated (Map-folder 7)
    Print, signature unclear (possibly Hy or Sy Arkin), undated, marked 18/98, 31 3/16" x 24 1/8" including 1/8" thick mat
  - Untitled print of watercolor landscape with windmill, Undated (Map-folder 8)
    Illegible signature, possibly A. Stemsten; undated; marked 95/135; 30 1/16" x 24 9/16" including 1/8" thick mat
  - Sheviti, 1958 (Map-folder 9)
    Original artwork; Rachamin Gedalia; 12th of Iyar, 1958; created "for Mr. Menashe ben Raphael"; pastels, ink, and pencil; 25 1/4" x 33" including 3/16" thick mat
  - Peace on Earth to Men of Good Will, Arthur Szyk, After 1946 (Map-folder 33)
    Published New York, 1942; reprinted by Sydney Hollaender, Ever Ready Label Corporation, after 1946; 15 1/16" x 17 1/16" including 3/8" thick mat
  - The United States of America, Arthur Szyk, After 1947 (Map-folder 34)
    Published New York, 1947; 16 9/16" x 19 1/16" including 3/16" thick mat
  - Jerusalem Pictorial and Descriptive: The Holy City in 19th Century Literature, 1997 (Map-folder 35)
    Exhibition poster, Boston College, 1997; 22" x 18 13/16" x 1/8"
  - Untitled etching of Man and Woman, probably Isaac and Rebecca, undated (Map-folder 36)
    Benjamin Levy (b. 1940); marked 112/150; 24" x 20 1/16" including 3/16" thick mat
  - Unbound sheet from Hagadat Volakh (The Wolloch Haggadah), Pessach Haggadah in Memory of the Holocaust, 1985 (Map-folder 37)
    Haifa, 1985; Illustrations by David Wander, calligraphy and micrography by Yonah Weinreb; 17 15/16" x 22 3/8" including 1/8" thick mat
  - Sheviti, undated (Map-folder 38)
    Undated; printed in color; 17" x 23" including 1/8" thick mat
  - Ushpizin wall hanging for sukkah, 1977 (Map-folder 39)
    Tel Aviv, 1977; 16" x 22 7/8" including 1/8" thick mat
  - Mizrah (Sheviti), undated (Map-folder 40)
    Undated; printed in color; 24" x 18" including 1/4" thick mat
  - Mizrah (Ushpizin), undated (Map-folder 41)
    Reprint, Jerusalem, undated; reproduced from original collection of Jewish wall mizrahim and pictures of M.M. Feldman, Jerusalem; 24" x 18" including 1/8" thick mat
  - Declaration of the Establishment of the State of Israel, Arthur Szyk, After 1948 (Map-folder 42)
    New Canaan, Connecticut; published 1948; 23 3/4" x 20" including 1/8" thick mat and translation page
  - Jerusalem 3000: Three Millenia of History, 1996 (Map-folder 10)
    Exhibition poster, Osher Map Library, Portland, Maine, 1996; 27" x 19 7/8" x 3/16"
  - Miracles Through Unity—Purim 1974 (Map-folder 11)
    Poster, The Israel Emergency Fund, 1974; 20" x 27 7/8" x 3/16"
  - Zog Nit Keynmol—We Survive!, 1976 (Map-folder 12)
    Poster, Tea Lautrec Litho, San Francisco, 1976; 23" x 25 3/8" x 3/16"
  - In Congress July 4, 1776, A Declaration by the Representatives of the United States of America, Arthur Szyk, After 1953 (Map-folder 13)
    Original copyright 1950, copyright 1953 Julia Szyk; 23" x 26 7/8" including 3/16" thick mat
  - Arthur Szyk Illuminator, After 1940 (Map-folder 14)
    Poster, copyright Historic Art, Yorba Linda, California, undated; artwork by Arthur Szyk, dated 1940; 23" x 27 7/8" including 1/8" thick mat
  - Share Chanukah with the Children of Israel: We Are One, Udated (Map-folder 15)
    Poster, The Israel Emergency Fund, undated; 21" x 27 7/8" x 3/16"
  - Israel on My Mind: Israel's Declaration of Independence, Undated (Map-folder 16)
    Nissan Engel, undated; 21 7/8" x 27 3/4" including 1/8" thick mat
  - Five Beloved Cities: Nachum Gutman, in Honor of his 80th Birthday, published by Jacques Soussana, 1978 (Map-folder 17)
    Goldman's Art Gallery, Haifa, 1978; 25 1/2" x 19 9/16"; one of two posters with identical text but different images: The poster in Folder 8 depicts a city lying among hills with trees in the foreground and panel including David's Harp, Menorah, Shofar, and other items of Judaica along the top.
  - Five Beloved Cities: Nachum Gutman, in Honor of his 80th Birthday, published by Jacques Soussana, 1978 (Map-folder 18)
    Goldman's Art Gallery, Haifa, 1978; 25 1/2" x 19 9/16"; one of two posters with identical text but different images: The poster in Folder 9 depicts black-hatted figures in the foreground and includes the artist's signature in the lower right-hand corner.
  - Miron Sima Woodcuts, Undated (Map-folder 19)
    Undated poster, 19 1/4" x 27 1/4"
  - Exhibition of Salvador Dali: Aliya, 1968 (Map-folder 20)
    Exhibition poster, Goldman's Art Gallery, Haifa, 1968; 19 9/16" x 27 3/16"
  - Marcel Janco: Watercolors 1940-1950, 1981 (Map-folder 21)
    Exhibition poster, Goldman's Art Gallery, Haifa, 1981; 26 13/16" x 18 15/16"
  - Brauer Haggadah, Undated (Map-folder 22)
    Poster, Goldman's Art Gallery, Haifa, undated; 17 7/8" x 27 1/4"
  - Art Expo NY, 1981 (Map-folder 23)
    Exhibition poster, Goldman's Art Gallery stand, New York Coliseum, 1981; 19 3/16" x 27 1/16"
  - Litvinovsky: Rabbis, 1978 (Map-folder 24)
    Poster, Goldman's Art Gallery, Haifa, 1978; 29 1/4" x 22 1/16"
  - Untitled print of rainbow, hearts, and stylized signature of Agam, Undated (Map-folder 25)
    Signed by Yaacov Agam (b. 1928), marked 67/200, undated; 20 5/8" x 29 1/2"
  - Marc Chagall: Posters 1953-1977 from the Collection of Goldman's Art Gallery, Haifa, 1978 (Map-folder 26)
    Exhibition poster, Haifa Museum of Modern Art, 1978; 21 3/4" x 32 5/8"
  - Michael Eisemann, 1981 (Map-folder 27)
    Exhibition poster, Goldman's Art Gallery (Haifa) stand, International Art Fair, Basel, 1981; 20 3/4" x 32 1/8"
  - Theo Tobiasse, 1981 (Map-folder 28)
    Poster, Goldman's Art Gallery, Haifa, 1981; 22 1/4" x 31"
  - Homage to Jerusalem: Jerusalem in Art, 1979 (Map-folder 29)
    Exhibition poster, Goldman's Art Gallery, Haifa, 1979; 21 9/16" x 32 5/8"
  - M. Shemi (1897-1951): Opening of a Permanent Exhibition, 1978 (Map-folder 30)
    Exhibition poster, Haifa Museum of Modern Art, 1978; 21 1/4" x 32 9/16"
  - Exhibition: Music in the Bible, The Bible in Music, 1979 (Map-folder 31)
    Exhibition poster, Haifa Museum, 1979; 21 3/4" x 32 7/8"
  - Chess in Art, 1976 (Map-folder 32)